Man, it's blowing like crazy out there. All I can see is snow, snow and more snow.
呀，外面风吹得太吓人了．我唯一能看见的是雪，除了雪还是雪
Quite an arctic storm blowing out there. Hmm! Come along Polly, my child, with my cloak.
外面刮着很强烈的极寒风暴．嗯，快来，Polly，孩子，带上我的斗篷
Hey Doctor, you've got the most fantastic wardrobe!
哈，博士，你的衣橱是最神奇的
Yes, well I'm glad you approve my child.
是的，我很高兴你赞同我的观点，孩子
These are gorgeous. Where do you shop, Carnaby street?! Ha ha!
它们太棒了．你都在哪儿买的，Carnaby 街吗？哈哈！
Who do you think you are, Nanook of the North or something?!
你觉得你像谁，北方的纳努克怎么样？!
(备注: Nanook of the North 是1992年无声记录片，记录了北极圈内的原住民纳努克家族艰苦的生活）
Oh now, now, now. Tcha, tcha, tcha. Stop being so flippant.
哦快快快，去去去，别这么轻浮了
We don't know what we are in for outside there. Now come along, come along, come along.
我们不知道到外面会碰到什么．快来吧，来吧，来吧
Here you are, Doctor.
这是你的，博士
Are you sure you're going to be warm enough?
你确定这样够暖和？
Oh, like toast my dear. Now, did you find everything you want?
噢，就像吐司面包一样，亲爱的．你都找到你想要的没有？
Yes thanks!
是的，谢谢
All right, well let's go outside and investigate. Go along.
好了，我们出去看看情况吧，快来
The Doctor was right about this being the coldest place on earth. I'm freezing already.
博士说对了，这地方的确是地球上最冷的地方．我已经冻死了
Yeah.
是啊
Hey, what's this?
嗨，这是什么？
Well watch it Polly!
注意点 Polly !
It's some kind of an aerial. There must be something buried underneath there.
这是某种天线．这下面肯定有什么东西
Hey, look over there, there's something moving.
嗨，看那儿，有什么东西在移动
Hey Tito, will you come over here?
嘿 Tito，过来一下好吗？
Oh, what is it?
哦，什么事？
Come over here quick! I can see people!
到这里，快点！我可以看到人！
Sure, sure, lots of people!
当然，当然，好多人！
- And there's a woman!   - A woman...
- 还有一个女人！  - 女人...
A WOMAN! Hey!
一个女人！嘿！
Hey, hey! Mama Mia bellissima!
嘿，嘿！妈妈咪呀！
Looks... looks like some kind of a hut.
看起来像是一个小屋
Quick, take those small arms, get upstairs and get... bring them down. Get moving!
快，带上那些小武器，上去把他们带下来，动起来！
I think we'd better go with 'em.
我觉得我们还是跟他们走吧
Move it, come on, hurry it up, come on, let's go, let's go, come on pops,
动起来，来吧，快点，来，走了走了，快点小伙子
Will you move it, will you move it pops, let's go, come on!
动一动，动一动行吗，走了，快点！
Please stop that. Please, please stop that.
请别催了．求你了，别喊了
Just a moment pops. Now who are you, and what are you doing here?
等一下，你们都是谁，在这里做什么？
Oh, we just landed outside.
噢，我们刚刚在外面降落
- What in?  - Well it's a sort of spaceship actually.
- 坐的什么？  - 嗯，实际上是一种飞船
- Ha ha! Some spaceship, box!   - You can knock off the jokes.
- 哈哈！某种飞船，盒子吧！ - 你可以收起你的笑话
She's not joking.
她没开玩笑
Look buddy, I want the truth, and quick.
听着伙计，我要的是实话，快说
Can you tell us precisely where we are please?
你能否告诉我们这是什么地方？
You're at the South Pole base of international space command, and frankly pops...
你们在南极国际宇航指挥中心基地，坦白的说伙计...
Doctor.
博士
...Doctor, your story's gonna have to be awful good.
...博士，你的故事一定是极好的
So you mean we are on Earth?
你的意思是说我们在地球上？
Well you heard, the South Pole.
是啊你都听到了，是南极
Oh boy. Tito, get the CO.
哦小伙，Tito，去找CO
He's a-not going to like it.
他不会喜欢这个
Get him!
去叫他！
Why don't you speak up, I'm deaf!
你为什么不再大声点，我聋了！
Who's the CO?
CO 是谁？
The Commanding Officer, the boss.
就是指挥官，老大
Hallo... Sir? Er, Private Tito, duty guard here.
哈罗，长官．我是值班士兵 Tito
Could you give a message to the General please?
请问你可否给将军递个消息？
- General?  - General Cutler, the CO.
- 将军？  - Cutler 将军，指挥官
Sir? I know, but this is an emergency! What's that? The General's not there?
长官？我知道，但这是紧急情况！什么？将军不在那儿？
Well canna you tell me where he is then?
那你可以告诉我他在那里吗？
Right here, Private.
就在这里，士兵
What is it Sergeant?
中士那里去了？
Ah, well sir...
啊，这个...长官...
Who are these people?
这些人都是什么人？
Well sir, they just appeared outside.
长官，他们是突然出现在外面的
What?
什么？
Yes sir, as I said they just appeared, from a hut.
是的，长官，如我所说他们是突然出现的，从一个小屋子里
A hut?!
一个小屋子？
Yes sir. Never been there before.
是的长官，之前并不在那里
That's a right General. That's just the way it happened.
是那样的，将军，的确就是这么回事
Well? Who are you?
那么，你们是谁？
Able seaman Ben Jackson sir, Royal Navy.
水手Ben Jackson，隶属皇家海军，长官
Then why aren't you with your ship?
那你怎么不在你的船上？
That's a bit difficult to explain sir.
解释起来有点困难，长官
Yeah, I'll bet my sweet life it is.
是啊，我拿我甜美的生活打赌是
We don't intend you any harm General, I can assure you of that.
我们没有任何恶意，将军，我可以向你保证
You can assure me of what you like, but whether I'll believe you or not is another question.
你想怎么保证都行，但我相不相信你们就是另外一回事
Huh, huh!
哈，哈！
I haven't got time to deal with these now, but when I do you'd better have a good explanation.
我现在没时间管这事，但回头我有时间了你们最好能有一个好的解释
I don't like your tone, sir.
我不喜欢你的语气，长官
And I don't like your face, nor your hair!
我也不喜欢你的脸，你的头发
Hmm!
哼！
Sergeant, bring him into Tracking and put him under guard in the observation room.
中士，把他带到追踪处，把他置于观察室的看守之下
I'll deal with them as soon as I have time.
等我一有时间了就来处理他们这事
Yes sir!
是，长官！
OK, come on, move...
好，快点，移动...
Hey, this is smashing. It looks just like that rocket place in America.
嘿，这很惊人啊．看起来跟那种美国火箭发射的地方差不多
Yeah, but I wonder why there are so few people.
是啊，不过我好奇为什么人那么少
I mean it's not like what you see on the telly, is it?
我是说并不像你在电视上看见的那样，是不？
I don't know what you see on your TV, son,
我不知道你在电视上看到的是怎样的，小子
but this is General Cutler's outfit. Come on, you'd better take a seat.
但这是 Cutler 将军的场所．过来，你们最好坐下
He don't like a lot of personnel, cuts down to the bare minimum and works them right into the ground.
他不喜欢很多人员，削减到最低限度，把他们直接投入地下
We only spend a couple of months on this station anyway. We can't stand more than that.
反正我们只在这里待两三个月而已．我们没法忍受太久
Ha ha ha!
哈哈哈！
I see. Hey, perhaps we can catch a lift back to England.
明白了．嗨，也许我们还可以赶上个回英格兰的顺风车呢
Oh, I can't see the squire there giving us a free lift to anywhere.
哦，我看那位绅士不会让我们免费搭车去任何地方
Well I don't want to depress you both but I'm afraid we're not quite where you think we are.
我不想让你们俩郁闷，但恐怕我们并不完全是在你们想象的地方
- What do you mean?  - What?
- 什么意思？ - 什么？
Well, just take a peek at that. Huh huh! Hmm!
咯，瞥一眼那个去．哼哼！哼！
1986! Oh no, and I thought we'd be able to get home.
1986！不是吧，我还以为我们可以回家了呢
Yeah, we're still at sea. Here, but that'll explain the few people.
是，我们还在海上．对了，这就解释了为什么这么少人了
The computers must do all the work now. Here, I wonder if they got to the moon yet.
所有的工作现在肯定是电脑干．嗨，我好奇他们登上月球没有
Sure, don't you listen to the news?
当然．你们就不听新闻的吗？
You mean you have sent people to the moon?
你是说你们已经把人送上月球了？
Yeah, an expedition just returned.
是，有支考察队刚回来
Well what's this flight then?
那这一次是飞哪儿？
Oh, this is just a normal atmosphere testing probe.
噢，这只是一个普通的大气测试探头
Yes, I see, a rocket testing site. Hum hum!
哦，明白了，一个火箭测试站，嗯嗯！
Hey, what's that?
嘿，那是什么？
An error? Where?
有错误？哪里？
Looks bad. We're now over south isle of New Zealand and reading a height of 1100 miles.
看起来不对，我们现在在新西兰南岛上空，高度数值是1100英里
1100? But that's impossible! Dyson, check what it should be, will you?
1100？那不可能啊！Dyson，检查设定值，好吗？
It should be 980.
设定值是980
No, it can't be, let me try.
不，不可能，我试试
Let me do it.
我来吧
No, you're right. 980 miles... they're out of position by more than a hundred miles!
不，你是对的，980英里...他们的位置偏了100多英里！
Mmm, looks like it.
嗯，看着像是
Snowcap to Zeus 4. Can you read me?
雪冠呼叫宙斯4号，你能听到吗？
Zeus 4 to Snowcap. Strength 8, over.
宙斯4号回复雪冠，强度为8．结束
Take visual checks on Mars to establish position. Report back.
参考火星进行目视检查，以确定位置，回报结果
Here we are. Well now, excuse me my dear...
好了．现在，打扰一下...
...er, take this to your General please.
...请把这个交给你们的将军
Me? Are you crazy?
我？你疯了吗？
Very well then, take me to the General. I think perhaps I can help him.
那好吧，带我去见将军．我想我可以帮上他
Oh I... I don't know.
噢...我不知道
Now look here Sergeant, this is urgent, I insist.
给我听着，中士，这事很紧急，我坚持
General, sir.
将军，长官
Yes, what is it?
嗯，什么事？
The old boy would like to have a word with you. Claims it's urgent.
这个老伙计想跟你说两句话，他说很紧急
OK, bring him over. But make it fast.
好，带他过来，不过动作要快
I think I know what you are going to see.
我想我知道你们将会看到什么
How can you possibly? Oh, get him back over there.
你怎么可能呢？噢，把他弄回那边去
I've written down here what he will see.
我已经写下了他将看到什么
Take your hands off me please!
请把你的手拿开！
Barclay! It's not very clear but it's a planet all right.
Barclay！这不是太清楚但应该是一颗行星
How could it be? Planets don't just appear.
这怎么可能？行星不可能就这么出现了
It must be on a weak orbit.
它肯定是在一个弱轨道上
It's approaching quite fast. Barclay, couldn't it be...
它正在快速接近．Barclay，它会不会...
I know what you're thinking. Zeus 4 is out of orbit and a new planet has appeared.
我知道你在想什么．宙斯4号偏离了轨道，又有一颗行星出现了...
Therefore the new planet is influencing Zeus 4. Right?
所以这颗行星会影响宙斯4号，对吧
That's about it.
就是这么回事
We must get them down!
我们必须把他们弄下来！
An emergency splash zone?
一个紧急溅射区域？
Yes. Snowcap calling Zeus 4, come in please. Zeus 4 come in please. Do you read me?
是．雪冠呼叫宙斯4号，请回话．宙斯4号请回话．你们能否听到？
Yes, we read you loud and clear.
听到，声音响亮而清晰
You are strength 2 only. Come in please, speak up.
你们的强度只有2级．请回话，大声点
Fuel cells are showing a power loss.
燃料电池显示有能量流失
Power loss?
能量流失？
Its gravity is affecting the capsule.
它的引力在影响太空舱
What shall we do about it?
我们怎么对付这个？
Well first of all we must give Zeus 4 a new correction path. Will you do that?
首先我们必须给宙斯4号一条修正路线，你能搞定吗？
Right away.
马上
You try and get a better fix on that so-called planet and see what it is.
你就尽力跟进那个所谓的行星，搞明白到底是个什么东西
Right sir.
是，长官
It's better now.
现在好点了
You say you know what this planet is. Well what is it?
你说你知道这个行星是什么，那它是什么？
Well I'm not quite sure sir. Let me have another look into this instrument.
呃我也不是太确定长官．我再去看一眼仪表
Feed the retina scope into the observations room's monitor.
把高清镜头的画面投到观察室的显示器上
Look Dr Barclay, let's just get those boys down.
Barclay 博士，我们去把那些小伙子弄下来
General, General, yes, it's just as I thought.
将军，将军，是的，的确如我所料
Come and have a look at these land masses.
过来看看这些大陆板块
Land masses? I don't see... I see what you mean.
大陆板块？我不明白...我明白你的意思了
Now, doesn't that remind you of anything, hmm?
现在，有没有想起一点什么？
Remind? No, I don't think so.
想起？不，我不觉得
Yeah, it looks familiar somehow.
是，这怎么看起来有点眼熟
Yeah. Hey Ben, look, that bit looks just like... Malaysia!
是啊，嘿 Ben，看，那块看起来像是...马来西亚
Oh, give over. No, hang on, isn't that... well it looks like South America but it can't be though!
哦，算了吧．不，等等，那不是...看起来像是南美洲，但这不可能啊！
Yes, there is a similarity.
的确，有一些相似性
Nonsense, how could there be?
胡说，怎么可能？
This is unbelievable. That's surely Africa?
这让人难以置信啊，那肯定就是非洲啰？
Yes, certainly and that is Malaysia!
是，那确定就是马来西亚
Ridiculous. There must be some reflection of Earth.
荒谬，肯定是某个地方反射出了地球的样子
No it can't be, there's nothing to reflect on!
这不可能，没有什么可反射的物质啊
And now my dear Dr Barclay I suggest you look at that piece of paper I gave you.
现在，亲爱的 Barclay 博士，我建议你看一下我给你的那张纸
Paper? Oh yes...
纸？噢，是的...
You knew!
你早知道！
Certainly.
当然
Knew what?
早知道什么？
He has correctly written down what we have just seen and he did it before we saw it.
他准确地写出了我们刚才看见的东西，但他是在我们看见之前写的
Oh, it's a... simple confidence trick, that's all.
哦，这是个...简单的障眼法，仅此而已
No, I know when he gave me the paper.
不，我知道他什么时候给我这张纸的
Now, you clearly know something more about the situation. Can you be more explicit?
对于当前的情况，你显然还知道些什么，你能说得更明白点吗
Yes sir, I'm sorry, I'm afraid I can.
是的先生，很抱歉，恐怕我能
You see, millions of years ago there was a twin planet to Earth and...
你知道吗，数百万年前，地球有一个孪生兄弟...
Oh, for heaven's sake!
噢，老天爷啊！
Roger, Zeus 4...
收到，宙斯4号...
Get me Geneva on the radio link.
给我接通日内瓦的无线电连接
We'll see what Wigner has to say about this.
我们看看 Wigner 对于这事有什么看法
You're looking terribly worried Doctor.
你看起来非常担心，博士
Am I my dear? Yes, I'm afraid I am rather worried.
是吗亲爱的？是的，恐怕我是真的担心
What is it Doctor? What's up?
是什么情况，博士？怎么了？
Well you see Ben, I know what this planet is and what it means to Earth.
哦你看 Ben，我知道这个星球是什么，对地球又意味着什么
And what does it mean to Earth?
对地球意味着什么？
Well, that pretty soon we shall be having visitors.
意味着，很快我们就会有客人来了
Now, suppose you tell me how you really came here.
现在，想来你可以告诉我，你实际上怎么来这里的
Yes, well I'm afraid all that's going to be rather difficult.
可以，只是恐怕那会相当困难
Now just a minute. You turn up out of nowhere, a routine space shot goes wrong...
等一等，你不知道从哪儿就钻出来了，例行的飞船发射出了问题...
a new planet appears and you tell us you know all about it. That puts you slap bang in the hot seat, right
一个新的行星冒出来了，你又说你对它很了解，fixme
Hot seat?
But we've got nothing to do with it.
但我们跟它没关系啊
That you're going to have to prove.
这个你们必须得证明
Well, I think if you allowed us to return where we came from, huh, huh! I...
我想如果你允许我们回到我们来的地方，呵，呵...
You're not going anywhere.
你那儿也别想去
- Sergeant?  - Yes sir?
- 中士？  - 什么事，长官？
- Have you searched that hut yet?  - No, sir
- 你们搜过那个小屋吗？ - 没有，长官
Well why not?! Look, I don't want any excuses, get out there and do it immediately.
为什么没有？我不想要任何借口，立即出去把这事办了
Now, perhaps we'll get to the bottom of this.
现在，也许我们可以得到这事的底细
Come on Tito, we have to go break into a hut.
来吧 Tito，我们必须得闯入那个小屋去
What, that thing out there?
什么，就那里那个东西？
Yeah, that's right. Come on, hurry up and get dressed up.
是的，就是这样．来吧，快点，穿上点
Oh, mama.
噢，妈呀
It's no good Tito, we'll need a welding torch to get inside this thing.
这没用的 Tito，我们要用焊枪才能进得去这里
Get back inside and bring me out one. You'll need some help, OK?
回到里面去，给我拿一个出来，找两个帮忙的，行吗？
Hurry up will ya, before I freeze to death!
快点行吗，要不然我要冻死了
What the heck? Huh, Tito! Is that you Tito?
什么鬼？啊，Tito！是你吗 Tito？
What's going on here? Who is that?
这里怎么回事？谁在那儿？
Who the heck are you?!
你到底是谁？
OK Joe, that should do it. OK, let's go.
好了 Joe，这应该可以了．好，我们走
Hey, this is where it is guys.
嘿，就是这个地方了伙计们